<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on The File Drawer</title>
    <link>https://filedrawer.blog/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on The File Drawer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filedrawer.blog/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol and Asteroids</title>
      <link>https://filedrawer.blog/post/oster_pregnancy_alcohol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filedrawer.blog/post/oster_pregnancy_alcohol/</guid>
      <description>I recently read Emily Oster’s book: Expecting Better: Why the Conventional Pregnancy Wisdom is Wrong—and What You Really Need to Know. Oster proposes using decision theory to use data on different activities during pregnancy to make decisions that best reflect your preferences.
The most controversial aspect of the book has been her claim that there is no risk to light drinking during pregnancy. This view has been criticized quite intensely, but I think these critiques don’t get to the heart of the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do cluster robust standard errors give false positives on cross-level interactions?</title>
      <link>https://filedrawer.blog/post/random-slopes-clustered-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filedrawer.blog/post/random-slopes-clustered-errors/</guid>
      <description>One of the most easy traps to fall into in quantitative social science is fooling yourself (and your statistics software) into thinking you have more information about a question than you really do.
As always, this is best illustrated with an XKCD comic:
The key point here is that there are only really three independent pieces of information (the three students) and the multiple observations of their yelling are just repeated measurements of the same piece of information rather than new information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
